Guide to the Time Inc. Corporate Administration Records 1853-2002 (bulk, 1929-1995) MS 3009-RG 5
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Vice President Otto Fuerbringer files on newspaper acquisition and development of a news wire service, 1954-1974 (bulk, 1968-1971); 8.5 Linear feet in 9 record cartons and 1 flat folder
  - Newspapers by state: California: Richmond: The Independent, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4264, Folder 11-14)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Hayward: The Daily Review, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4264, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Hollywood: Citizen-News and Valley Times, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 4264, Folder 16-17)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Palo Alto Times, 1970 (Offsite-box 4264, Folder 18-19)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Van Nuys: Green Sheet, 1970 (Offsite-box 4264, Folder 20-21)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Times Mirror Company, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspapers by state: California: Sacramento, 1968 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers by state: California: San Bernardino, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 4-5)
  - Newspapers by state: California: San Francisco and Bay Area, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 6-9)
  - Newspapers by state: Colorado: General, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 10-12)
  - Newspapers by state: Colorado: The Record Stockman, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers by state: Connecticut, 1967-1970 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers by state: Delaware, circa 1969 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers by state: District of Columbia: General, 1970 (Offsite-box 4265, Folder 16-17)
  - Newspapers by state: District of Columbia: Army Times Publishing Company, 1969 (Offsite-box 4266, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspapers by state: District of Columbia: The Morning News, 1971 (Offsite-box 4266, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers by state: District of Columbia: Washington Star, 1966-1974 (Offsite-box 4266, Folder 4-10)
  - Newspapers by state: Florida: General, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 4266, Folder 11-12)
  - Newspapers by state: Florida: Perry newspapers, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 4266, Folder 13-18)
  - Newspapers by state: Georgia, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: General, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 2-5)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Barrington Press, 1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 6)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Buffalo Grove Reminder, 1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Buffalo Grove Reminder [RESTRICTED], 1970 (Offsite-box R65)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Free Press Newspaper Group, 1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Day Publications / Tri-County Press / Buffalo Grove Reminder, 1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 9)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Chicago News, 1967-1968 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 10)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Chicago Sun Times, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 11)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Chicago Tribune, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers by state: Illinois: Paddock Publications, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers by state: Kansas, 1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers by state: Massachusetts: General, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers by state: Massachusetts: Boston area: General, 1969 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers by state: Massachusetts: Boston Globe, 1968 (Offsite-box 4267, Folder 17-19)
  - Newspapers by state: Massachusetts: Boston Herald-Traveler Corporation, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspapers by state: Massachusetts: Fall River Herald News, 1966 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers by state: Michigan: General, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 4-6)
  - Newspapers by state: Michigan: Detroit News, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers by state: Minnesota, 1970 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 8-9)
  - Newspapers by state: Missouri, 1968 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 10)
  - Newspapers by state: Nebraska, 1970 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 11)
  - Newspapers by state: New Hampshire, 1968 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 12)
  - Newspapers by state: New Jersey, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 13-14)
  - Newspapers by state: New Mexico, 1967 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: General, 1966-1970 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 16-17)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: Newsday, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 18-19)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: Experimental papers, 1954-1955 (Offsite-box 4268, Folder 20)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: Wall Street Journal, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 1-2)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: The New York Times, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: Business World, 1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers by state: New York: Journal of Commerce, 1968 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers by state: Ohio: General, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 6-8)
  - Newspapers by state: Ohio: Berea Publishing Company, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 9)
  - Newspapers by state: Ohio: The Cincinnati Enquirer, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 10-12)
  - Newspapers by state: Ohio: Metro newspapers, 1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers by state: Ohio: The Plain Dealer, 1968 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers by state: Oklahoma, 1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers by state: Oregon, 1968 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers by state: Pennsylvania, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 17)
  - Newspapers by state: Tennessee, 1968 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 18)
  - Newspapers by state: Texas, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 19)
  - Newspapers by state: Utah [empty], circa 1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 20)
  - Newspapers by state: Vermont, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 21)
  - Newspapers by state: Virginia, 1969 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 22)
  - Newspapers by state: Washington, 1968 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 23)
  - Newspapers by state: Wisconsin, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4269, Folder 24)
  - Time-Life News: General, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 1-5)
  - Time-Life News: Budget, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 6-7)
  - Time-Life News: Contact reports, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 8)
  - Time-Life News: Contract background, 1969? (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 9)
  - Time-Life News: Dry run proofs, 1969 (Offsite-box 4271, Folder 6)
  - Time-Life News: Experimental run, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 10)
  - Time-Life News: Film experiment payments, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 11)
  - Time-Life News: Journals, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 12)
  - Time-Life News?: Microwave industry, 1966-1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 13)
  - Time-Life News: Miscellaneous payments, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 14)
  - Time-Life News?: New Service: Television, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 15)
  - Time-Life News: Original proposals, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 16)
  - Time-Life News: Photograph payments, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 17)
  - Time-Life News: Press clippings, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 18)
  - Time-Life News: Rates, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 19)
  - Time-Life News: Research?, 1969? (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 20)
  - Time-Life News?: Syndication, 1965-1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 21)
  - Acquisition: Lloyd Hollister Inc. and North Shore Publishing Company: General, 1969 (Offsite-box 4270, Folder 22-23)
  - Acquisition: Lloyd Hollister Inc. and North Shore Publishing Company: General [RESTRICTED] (3 folders), 1969 (Offsite-box R65)
  - Acquisition: Lloyd Hollister Inc. and North Shore Publishing Company: Purchase agreement [RESTRICTED] (2 folders), 1969 (Offsite-box R65)
- Series XII. Vice President of Administrative Services Rosemarie Di Sapio Files, 1986-1996; 4.25 Linear feet in 6 record cartons
  Rosemarie Di Sapio joined Time Inc. in 1961 as the secretary to the director of communications. She held positions on the business side of Sports Illustrated beginning in 1966 culimating in a position as the associate business manager from 1973 to 1977. From 1978 to 1980 she was the business manager of Money. She briefly held the position of Time-Life Films director of personnel and administration before being promoted to the Video Group director of finance and administration. At the end of 1985, she was named the corporate director of administration. In April 1987 she is listed as the director of administrative services for the Magazine Group which seems like the same role as before, but within the new Time Warner company structure. In August 1987, she is promoted to vice president of administrative services. The 1992 department heads list has her as the vice president of Magazine Administrative Services which sounds like it is still the same role within the Magazine Group of Time Warner. The Magazine Group later reverted to a subsidiary called Time Inc.
  According to a job description in Di Sapio's bio file, the director of administration supported the chief administrative officer. The CAO oversaw ISG (which is not defined), human resources, international administration, and the corporate business office. Magazine Administrative Services in 1992 oversaw Security, Dining, Telecommunication, Travel Services, and Facilities Management. Announcements about Di Sapio's promotions never state that she was taking over duties from retiring vice president Charles Bear although their roles were similar in some ways.
  Vice President of Administration Rosemarie Di Sapio files include her records as vice president and director of this office. Records include memoranda and documents from corporate offices regarding expenses and staff movement; files regarding the expenses related to meetings and conferences; and records regarding overhauls in staffing numbers at Time Inc. The personnel files kept by Di Sapio's office include performance reviews, termination agreements and payouts, and a small amount of court records.
  Archives transfer forms for Di Sapio's files are in her bio file (MS 3009-RG 2). Her files were sent to the Time Inc. Archives between 1988 and 1991. It looks like a large amount of her files were either culled prior to acquisition by the New-York Historical Society or possibly dispersed into one of the assembled collections created by the Time Inc. Archives.
  Organized into two series:
  Series XII.A. Office Files
  Series XII.B. Personnel Files
  - Series XII.A. Office Files, 1986-1995; 1.75 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    - File transfer list, undated (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 1)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: American Television and Communications Corporation, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 2)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Brooks and Information Services, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 3)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Corporates Group, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 4)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Feedback, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 5)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Guest lists, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 6)
    - Conference/Meetings: Home Box Office (HBO), 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 7)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Magazines, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 8-9)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Preliminary arrangements, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 10)
    - Conference/Meetings: Executive briefing dinners: Speeches, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 11)
    - Conference/Meetings: External group meetings, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 12)
    - Conference/Meetings: Financial conference, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 13)
    - Conference/Meetings: Senior management meetings: General, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 14-15)
    - Conference/Meetings: Senior management meetings: Lyford Cay, 1987 June 22-25 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 16)
    - Conference/Meetings: Staff briefings: 1981, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 17)
    - Corporate Finance: Capital appropriations, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 18)
    - Corporate Finance: Critical success factors, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 19)
    - Corporate Finance: Estimates, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 20)
    - Corporate Finance: Loans, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 21)
    - Corporate Finance: Policies, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 22)
    - Corporate Finance: 10K 1985, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 23)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Chairman's Office, 1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 24)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Chairman's Office: Executive Committee, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 25)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Community Relations, 1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 26)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Corporate Administration, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 27)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Corporate Business Office, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 28)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Corporate Finance: Organization, 1985 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 29)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Corporate Finance: Schedules, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 30)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Corporate Systems Administration, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 31)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Coudrai, Marcelle, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 32)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: International Business Development, 1986 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 33)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Investor Relations, 1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 34)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: FYI, 1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 35)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Operations Research, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 36)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Public Affairs: Corporate Contributions, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4284, Folder 37)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: SAMI/Burke, Inc. [Selling Areas Marketing, Inc.], 1987 (Offsite-box 4285, Folder 1)
    - Corporate Overhead Departments: Systems Administration, 1987 (Offsite-box 4285, Folder 2)
    - Finance: Corporate Business Office: Reserve: 1986 [RESTRICTED], 1986-1987 (Offsite-box R17)
    - Finance: Reserve: Reduction in force: 1986, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 4285, Folder 3-4)
    - Finance: Reserve: Reduction in force: 1986 [RESTRICTED] (2 folders), 1987-1988 (Offsite-box R17)
    - Finance: Reserve: Reduction in force: Unfiled documents [RESTRICTED] (2 folders), 1988 (Offsite-box R17)
    - Newstour '95: Planning binder, 1995 (Offsite-box 4285, Folder 5-8)
  - Series XII.B. Personnel Files [RESTRICTED], 1987-1996; 2.5 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
    The files in the boxes have not been reorganized.
    - Personnel files, 1987-1995 (Offsite-box 646, Folder 1-28)
    - Personnel files, 1987-1993 (Offsite-box 647, Folder 1-55)
    - Personnel files, 1987-1996 (Offsite-box 4286, Folder 1-11)
- Series XIII. Director of International Business Development William S. Rukeyser Files, 1965-1988 (bulk, 1986-1988); 2.25 Linear feet in 3 record cartons
  In 1986, Editor-in-Chief Henry Grunwald appointed William S. Rukeyser to a one-year assignment as the director of international business development to explore international publishing opportunities. This newly created position initially reported to Executive Vice President of Magazines Kelso Sutton. In this role, Rukeyser set up a joint venture to publish a French-language version of Fortune.
  Rukeyser joined Time Inc. in 1967 as an associate editor at Fortune. In 1972, he was appointed the founding managing editor of the new magazine Money. After overseeing Money for eight years, Rukeyser moved back to Fortune as its managing editor and remained there until his final post at Time Inc. as director of international business development. Rukeyser left Time Inc. in 1988.
  "Rukeyser Moves On." FYI, February 18, 1988.
  William Rukeyser's files document his work researching publishing Time Inc. magazines or new magazines in the international market. His research includes the issue if articles from the original Time Inc. magazies could be directly translated or if additional editing and rewriting was required. Rukeyser explored partnerships with publishers outside of the United States such as Gruner + Jahr and Singapore Press Holdings Ltd Group. He also received a proposal from Sinolink Group for a Chinese edition of Time magazine. Rukeyser also researched other types of media markets including television and VCR use. Time Inc. contracted consultant Lee B. Hall for this project, and Rukeyser's files include extensive correspondence with opinions and research reports from Hall.
  Rukeyser's role at the corporate management level overlapped in function with the Time Inc. International department although he was not part of this department. Further records on Time Inc.'s international publishing ventures are in Time Inc. International Records (MS 3009-RG 56).
  Organized alphabetically with general files before files organized by geographic name. Arrangement imposed by the archivist.
  - General: Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 1-4)
  - General: Automated Language Processing System (ALPS), 1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 5)
  - General: Automated Language Processing System (ALPS) [RESTRICTED], 1987 (Offsite-box R16)
  - General: Hall, Lee B., 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 6-8)
  - General: Hall, Lee B. [RESTRICTED], 1986-1987 (Offsite-box R16)
  - General: History [of Time Inc. international publishing], 1965-1986 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 9-10)
  - General: New Fortune proposals, 1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 11)
  - General: New magazine proposals, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 12)
  - General: Presentation: International taskforce, 1986 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 13)
  - General: Presentations: To management, 1986 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 14-15)
  - General: Special projects, 1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 16)
  - General: Worldwide market ranking, 1986 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 17)
  - Asia: General, 1973-1987 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 18-22)
  - Asia: Far Eastern Economic Review, 1986 (Offsite-box 4275, Folder 23)
  - Australia: General, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 1)
  - Australia: General [RESTRICTED], 1986-1987 (Offsite-box R16)
  - China: General, 1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 2)
  - China: Chinese version of Time, 1986 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 3)
  - England: General, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 4-5)
  - England: EMAP plc, 1986-1988 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 6)
  - Europe: European television, 1986 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 7-9)
  - Germany: General, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 10-11)
  - Germany: Bertelsmann, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 12)
  - Germany: German Fortune: General, 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 13-16)
  - Germany: German Fortune: Financial, 1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 17)
  - Germany: Industriemagazin, 1988 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 18)
  - Italy: RAI-Radiotelevisione italiana, 1986 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 19)
  - Japan: Diamond-Time / President, 1985-1987 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 20)
  - Japan: Japanese People / Focus / Asian People proposal, 1986 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 21)
  - Spain: General, 1987-1988 (Offsite-box 4276, Folder 22)